Vivian Chen

vivianc206@gmail.com | 917.353.2308 | Github | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Urban data scientist with 3+ years of experience in creating and aggregating data, generating visualizations, and writing documentation. Strong interests in understanding urban infrastructure patterns, public transportation accessibility, and intuitive design. Seeking full time fall opportunities to apply and enhance data mining and programming skills to create solutions for real-life applications, urban issues, and company efficiency.

EDUCATION AND HONORS

NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress

Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics

- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning for Cities, Big Data Management and Analytics, Democracy for Cities, Urban Spatial Analytics; Applied Data Science; Principles of Urban Informatics; Data Governance Ethics & Privacy
- Capstone Project with sponsor Office of Nightlife, NYC Mayor's Office of Media and Entertainment
 - o Pathways to Legal Occupancy: Preserving Nightlife Cultural Spaces

Macaulay Honors College at Hunter College (CUNY)

New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts in Geographical Information Science

08/2015 - 06/2019

Expected Graduation: 07/2020

Member of Gamma Theta Upsilon (2019)

SKILLS

- Coding Languages and Database Applications: Python, SQL, VBA, Microsoft Access
- GIS Software: ArcGIS, QGIS
- **Design:** HTML, CSS, Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator)

Minors in Computer Science and Media Studies

• Languages: English (native), Mandarin (conversational), Cantonese (conversational), French (basic)

WORK EXPERIENCE

New York City Economic Development Corporation

01/2020 - Present

Transportation Intern (Planning Department)

- Analysis on residents' MTA travel patterns to determine potential housing development locations using publicly available data, Python, and Excel
- Compiling and standardizing bathymetry data for NYC waterfronts under NYCEDC jurisdiction

New York City Department of Transportation

GIS College Aide (Asset Management Unit)

03/2018 - 02/2020

- Built and maintained geodatabases through customized scripts using Python, SQL, and VBA
- Created and updated maps and metadata of NYCDOT assets through ArcMap, ArcCatalog, and QGIS
- Generated dashboards using MS Excel and MS Access for data visualization and projection analysis
- Through MS Access, designed a database to track seating arrangements for all DOT floors within the 55 Water St. building to streamline the agency's emergency preparedness procedures

Barnard College, Empirical Reasoning Center

08/2019 - 12/2019

08/2017 - 01/2019

Teaching Assistant (Intro to GIS Methods)

• Supported Prof. Alisa Rod by guiding students on using GIS, grading labs, and holding weekly office hours

The Graduate Center, City University of New York

Research Intern

• Conducted research to create a database of NYC architecture and generated an interactive map via CARTO for Dr. Elizabeth Macaulay-Lewis' publication: Classical New York Discovering Greece and Rome in Gotham

American Geographical Society

Scholar Intern 09/2016 - 12/2016

- Published weekly Spotlight articles on world news and interviews with companies and non-profit organizations on AGS blogging sites UBIQUE and Connect2Conserve
- Prepared for the annual Fall Symposium, *Geography 2050* by creating graphics for promotional items, advertising on social media, and working on-site to ensure a smooth run-of-the-show